His past was kept from him, his search for answers has just begun.
The Amazing Spider-Man is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Marc Webb.
Peter Parker is an outcast high schooler abandoned by his parents as a
boy, leaving him to be raised by his Uncle Ben and Aunt May.
Like most teenagers, Peter is trying to figure out who he is
and how he got to be the person he is today.
As Peter discovers a mysterious briefcase that belonged to his father, he begins a quest to
understand his parents' disappearance – leading him directly to Oscorp and the lab of Dr.
Curt Connors, his father's former partner.
As Spider-Man is set on a collision course with Connors' alter ego, The Lizard, Peter will make
life-altering choices to use his powers and shape his destiny to become a hero.
Spider-Man / Peter Parker, played by Andrew Garfield.
Gwen Stacy, played by Emma Stone.
The Lizard / Dr. Curt Connors, played by Rhys Ifans.
Captain Stacy, played by Denis Leary.
Uncle Ben, played by Martin Sheen.
Aunt May, played by Sally Field.
The Amazing Spider-Man is a 2012 American superhero film
based on the Marvel Comics character Spider-Man.
Directed by Marc Webb and written by James Vanderbilt, Alvin Sargent, and Steve Kloves
from a story by Vanderbilt, it is a reboot of the Spider-Man film series.
Andrew Garfield stars as Peter Parker / Spider-Man alongside Emma Stone, Rhys Ifans,
Denis Leary, Campbell Scott, Irrfan Khan, Martin Sheen, and Sally Field.
The plot of the film follows the teenager Peter Parker, who gains spider-like abilities and
fights crime as Spider-Man, while also attempting to live an ordinary life.
Development of the film began in 2010 following the cancellation of Spider-Man 4, which would
have been the fourth film in Sam Raimi's Spider-Man series starring Tobey Maguire.
Columbia Pictures opted to reboot the franchise with the same production team, with
Vanderbilt staying on to write, and Sargent and Kloves assisting with the script.
Using the RED Epic camera, principal photography started in December
2010 in Los Angeles before moving to New York City.
The film entered post-production in April 2011.
3ality Technica provided 3D image processing, while Sony
Pictures Imageworks handled CGI effects.
It was the last film written by Sargent before his death in 2019.
Sony Pictures Entertainment built a promotional website, releasing many previews and launching a
viral marketing campaign, with tie-ins including a video game by Beenox and Activision.
The Amazing Spider-Man premiered in Tokyo on June 30, 2012, and was released in
2D, 3D, IMAX 3D, and 4DX formats in the United States on July 3.
It received mostly positive reviews from critics, who praised the directing, action
sequences, visual effects, musical score, and the performances of Garfield and Stone.
The film grossed $758.7 million worldwide, making it the
seventh-highest-grossing film of 2012.
A sequel, The Amazing Spider-Man 2, was released in 2014.
In 2021, Garfield and Ifans reprised their roles in the Marvel Cinematic Universe film Spider-Man: No Way Home, which explored the
concept of the multiverse and linked the Spider-Man series directed by Jon Watts to the films directed by Webb and Raimi.
The film explores themes of experiment, loss of loved
one, superhero, based on comic, vigilante.
The tone is thought_provoking.